"My Perfect Stranger"
《我的完美陌生人》
"Kim Dong-wook"
“金东旭”
"Kim Ki Joo"
《金基珠》
"My Perfect Stranger"
《我的完美陌生人》
It's been exactly one year since now...
距离现在整整一年了...
…I’ll die when I’m 35.
……我35岁那年就会死。
Because my murderer is the real murderer...
因为杀了我的凶手才是真正的凶手……
...1987 Uzhongli Serial Murder Case.
……1987 年乌中里连环杀人案。
That was the mark of a criminal in 1987.
那是1987年罪犯的标志。
This was also found at the scene of my murder.
这也是在我被谋杀的现场发现的。
How did he get this?
他是怎么得到这个的？
He is a new student and will join your class from today.
他是一名新学生，从今天起将加入你们班。
Her name is Bai Yunying.
她的名字叫白允英。
Don't act like we're friends. do you want to die
别表现得像我们朋友一样。你想死吗
Nice to meet you. My name is Liu Fanlong.
很高兴见到你。我叫柳范龙。
- Be careful. - What?
- 当心。- 什么？
Do you think my sister will run away from you?
你认为我姐姐会逃离你吗？
because I like you.
因为我喜欢你。
How do you know I'm there?
你怎么知道我在那里？
The first suspect in the impending murder...
即将发生的谋杀案的第一个嫌疑人......
...Three days later, Baek Hee-seop.
……三天后，白熙燮。
The second suspect Liu Fanlong.
第二名嫌疑人柳范龙。
The third suspect was jailed for 30 years…
第三名嫌疑人被判入狱30年……
...After being convicted, Gao Minxiu.
...被定罪后，高敏秀。
All these people you meet today.
您今天遇到的所有这些人。
"My Perfect Stranger" Episode 4, is this all a coincidence?
《我的完美陌生人》第4集，这一切都是巧合吗？
Who are you?
你是谁？
Why are you here?
你为什么来这里？
what are you saying?
你在说什么？
“Bong Bong Tea Shop”
“Kedai Teh Bong Bong”
How could this happen to you?
这怎么会落到你身上呢？
It was on the floor, so I picked it up.
它在地板上，所以我把它捡了起来。
It's too bad if you try to hide it.
如果你试图隐藏它，那就太糟糕了。
Why should I hide what I collect?
为什么我要隐藏收集到的东西？
no. I collected it.
不是。我收集了它。
I also quoted it accidentally.
我也是偶然引用的。
Did you pick it up by chance?
你是偶然捡到的吗？
when and where?
何时何地？
Before I got here.
在我到达这里之前。
Just an hour before you hit me.
就在你打我的前一个小时。
I saw this floating object by the river in this village.
我在这个村子的河边看到了这个漂浮物。
I took it without thinking.
我想都没想就拿走了。
"By the river."
“在河边。”
What are you doing so late?
这么晚了你在做什么？
I...
我...
"Dear Yoon Young"
《亲爱的尹英》
Ada...
艾达...
Is this another thing you can't tell me?
这是另一件事你不能告诉我吗？
Just like why you want to meet Go Min Soo.
就像你为什么要见高民秀一样。
I just have a few questions for him.
我只是有几个问题要问他。
That's all I can explain right now.
我现在能解释的就是这些。
OK
好的。
That's all we can talk about.
这就是我们能谈论的一切。
You still have not answered my question.
你还没有回答我的问题。
When I asked you how you knew I was there...
当我问你怎么知道我在那儿时...
...You just need to give it to me...
……你只要给我……
...this.
...这。
What's this?
这是什么？
What does this mean to you?
这对你来说意味着什么？
The things that got me here.
让我来到这里的事情。
Something I have to keep looking for.
我必须继续寻找的东西。
Everything that happens has a cause and effect.
一切发生的事情都有因果关系。
That's all I can tell you right now.
我现在能告诉你的就是这些。
Unfortunately, it seems...
不幸的是，似乎...
...Neither of us was ready to tell the other.
...我们都没有准备好告诉对方。
Yes. that's right.
是的。这是正确的。
May 11, 1987.
1987 年 5 月 11 日。
Three days before the first murder.
第一起谋杀案发生前三天。
This is a critical moment...
这是一个关键时刻...
…But the past as I knew it has changed.
......但我所知道的过去已经改变了。
A new event has occurred.
发生了新事件。
The prime suspect...no.
主要嫌疑人……不。
Gao Minxiu, who was accused of being the real murderer...
被指控为真凶的高敏秀……
... was detained by the police.
……被警察拘留了。
What happens now?
现在会发生什么？
You chose that one...
你选了那个...
...coincidence?
……巧合吗？
“Bong Bong Tea Shop”
“Kedai Teh Bong Bong”
What is he hiding?
他在隐藏什么？
Why does he have such an expression?
他为什么露出这样的表情？
"Wuzhong Police Station"
「吴中警察署」
"What did you do after that?"
“那之后你做了什么？”
That's all we can tell you.
这就是我们能告诉你的一切。
OK This is fine now. You can go back now.
好的。现在这样很好。你现在可以回去了。
"Detective Part 2"
《侦探二部》
He doesn't want to talk.
他不想说话。
That's good news.
那是好消息。
He wasted his time.
他耽误了自己的时间。
What do you mean?
你是什​​么意思？
People like him should be locked up in jail for as long as possible...
像他这样的人就应该被关在监狱里，越久越好……
...for the safety of this village.
……为了这个村庄的安全。
We don't know what else he'll do.
我们不知道他还会做什么。
So, keep doing this.
所以，继续这样做。
Don't say or do anything.
不要说任何话或做任何事。
sitting there...
坐在那儿...
...and try not leaving the house for a week.
...并尝试持续一周不出门。
If nothing happens that week...
如果那周什么都没发生的话...
…It will confirm that you killed them.
……它将确认是你杀了他们。
Otherwise you will be proven innocent.
否则你将被证明是无辜的。
"Kill them?"
“杀了他们？”
useless. what are you saying?
无用。你在说什么？
Shut up, useless kid!
闭嘴，没用的孩子！
Please keep an eye on him.
请密切关注他。
"Balay City"
《巴莱城》
What does this mean to him?
这件事对他来说意味着什么？
No I'm fine.
不我没事。
it's all over. I'm fine now.
一切都结束了。我现在没事了。
"troll"
“巨魔”
I really have lost my appetite.
我实在是没有胃口了。
You haven't eaten anything.
你什么也没吃。
You should eat something first before you can get a good night's sleep.
你应该先吃点东西才能睡个好觉。
We're not close enough to eat together.
我们距离不够近，无法一起吃饭。
"Codade"
“科戴德”
“H Tea Shop”
“Kedai Teh H”
He wants me to drink coffee on an empty stomach?
他要我空腹喝咖啡？
Is this the name of the teahouse?
这是茶馆的名字吗？
Unique.
独特的。
Hey. Can we be open for another 30 minutes today?
嘿。今天可以再开放 30 分钟吗？
All restaurants are closed.
所有餐馆都关门了。
I can’t let women starve on dates.
我不能让女人在约会时挨饿。
no. I never said...
不是。我从来没有说过...
well.
唉。
No.
不。
Why do teahouses sell this?
为什么茶馆里卖这个？
Just like the original poster.
就像楼主一样。
He is quite unique.
他是相当独特的。
He also enjoys taking care of other people's clothes.
他还喜欢打理别人的衣服。
Oh yes, people nowadays...
哦，是的，现在的人们...
...sauce the bread?
...给面包打酱油？
I have no idea.
我不知道。
None of the bread tasted salty.
没有面包尝起来是咸的。
Try their bread.
尝尝他们的面包。
I have no appetite...
我没有胃口...
…but you already bought it…
……但是你已经买了……
Do you really like salty and sweet food?
你真的喜欢吃咸的和甜的食物吗？
Don’t you know this is a must for modern people?
难道你不知道这是现代人必须的吗？
For a month, I finished my work every morning…
一个月来，我每天早上都完成工作……
...to meet deadlines.
...以满足最后期限。
When I want to relax on the weekend...
当我周末想放松的时候...
...I manage my phone as a writer...
...我管理手机的作家...
...complains about pen ink he doesn't like...
...抱怨他不喜欢的钢笔墨水...
...It made me lose my will to live.
……让我失去了活下去的意志。
But sweet and salty food...
但又甜又咸的食物...
...seems to have revived me.
……似乎让我复活了。
Have you ever worked for a publishing company?
您曾经在出版公司工作过吗？
Are you an editor?
你是编辑吗？
And you?
你呢？
I lost my job.
我失业了。
certainly. You don't want to tell me.
当然。你不想告诉我。
I'm the only one telling the truth.
我是唯一一个说实话的人。
not like this.
不是这样的。
Oops, this is the worst.
哎呀，这是最糟糕的。
sorry.
对不起。
You don't have to apologize. Our tastes are different.
你不必道歉。我们的口味不同。
I promise not to trouble you.
我保证不麻烦你。
But I got you to the station.
但我让你到了车站。
I am really sorry.
我真的很抱歉。
But you weren't the one who made this happen.
但你并不是让这一切发生的人。
Whatever you want to ask him or something else...
无论你想问他什么事情还是其他问题......
...This kind of thing shouldn't happen...
……这样的事情不应该发生……
...even if you follow him for some reason.
...即使你出于某种原因跟随他。
This problem is his, not yours.
这个问题是他造成的，不是你造成的。
You don't have to apologize.
你不必道歉。
Don't be too scared.
别太害怕。
I won't let that happen.
我不会让这种事发生。
I'll make sure the light is fixed as soon as possible.
我会确保灯尽快修好。
"Pavagam Wu Zheng"
《帕瓦加姆·吴正》
Do you think you can run?
你觉得你能跑吗？
certainly.
当然。
They are so crazy.
他们太疯狂了。
Why do donuts add soy sauce?
甜甜圈为什么要加酱油呢？
wheat.
麦。
Go in and finish this thing quietly.
进去安静的把这件事做完吧。
do not tell anyone.
不要告诉任何人。
OK
好的。
“Bong Bong Tea Shop”
“Kedai Teh Bong Bong”
What's his story?
他有什么故事呢？
I left early because I still had things to do.
我很早就离开了，因为我还有事要做。
Eat breakfast, bring food...
吃早餐，带食物...
...and then went to Shun Ai's house across the street.
...然后去了街对面顺爱家。
Of course, they are waiting for you. I told them earlier.
当然，他们正在等你。我早些时候告诉过他们。
Make sure to apply more medication to the wound.
确保在伤口上涂抹更多的药物。
You don't have to wash the dishes. Just place it in the sink.
你不必洗碗。只需将其放入水槽即可。
do not be late.
不要迟到。
She chattered like a mother.
她像母亲一样喋喋不休。
"A wonderful and extraordinary life"
“精彩非凡的人生”
mark!
马克！
- Mrs! - How is this going?
- 太太！- 这是怎么回事？
Mom, can't you see my shiny leggings?
妈妈，你没看到我闪亮的紧身裤吗？
I might be late for the salon.
我去沙龙可能会迟到。
it's useless.
没用的。
You get drunk during the day and make a scene at night.
你白天喝醉了，晚上就闹腾了。
Oops, mommy needs to make fried eggs for Wu Fu.
哎呀，妈妈需要给吴福做煎鸡蛋。
- Honey. - Yes?
- 亲爱的。- 是的？
Why are there no good socks?
为什么没有好的袜子？
You took a pair from the basket, not the closet, right?
你从篮子里拿了一双，而不是从衣柜里拿的，对吗？
I said I put the socks with holes in the basket.
我说我把破洞的袜子放进篮子里了。
Why do you always take...
为什么你总是拿...
- ...from there? - Mrs! No tissues.
- ...从那里？- 太太！没有纸巾。
Oh yes. Let me get it.
哦是的。让我来拿一下。
Mom, I asked about my tights first.
妈妈，我先问了我的紧身衣。
where is my wallet
我的钱包在哪里
Oh yes. I also changed my pants. My purse
哦是的。我也换了裤子。我的钱包
- What? - My purse.
- 什么？- 我的钱包。
- I didn't take out your wallet. - Mrs.
- 我没有拿出你的钱包。- 太太。
- Mom, are the fried eggs ready? - Fried eggs?
- 妈妈，煎鸡蛋准备好了吗？- 煎鸡蛋？
Not again.
不会再有。
You can't feel the kimbap directly.
你无法直接感受到紫菜包饭。
- Really? - what are you saying?
- 真的吗？- 你在说什么？
Eat. Mom, you always make plain kimbap.
吃吧。妈妈，您总是做朴素的紫菜包饭。
It's time for you to eat too.
你也该吃饭了。
well.
唉。
That useless book!
那本无用的书！
You have finished folding...
你已经折叠完了...
...fried eggs for your sister.
...为你妹妹煎鸡蛋。
Now. Stop folding.
现在。别再折叠了。
Go cook some fried eggs for Wu Fu.
去给吴福煮煎鸡蛋吧。
Now.
现在。
OK
好的。
Hello?
你好？
I'll be back in a moment.
我一会儿就回来。
Are you Wu Bo?
你是吴博吗？
Who are you?
你是谁？
This is me, sir. Yin Yong.
这就是我，先生。尹永.
What's wrong?
怎么了？
Who are you...
你是谁...
...standing on my page and blinking your big eyes?
...站在我的页面上眨着你的大眼睛？
Dato?
拿督？
This is me. Yin Ying!
这就是我。尹英！
I may not have enough time to change my socks.
我可能没有足够的时间换袜子。
Give me a pair quickly.
快给我一双。
- Honey! - I am coming!
- 亲爱的！- 我来了！
Stop calling me!
别再给我打电话了！
after that...
在那之后...
well.
唉。
Hello, Teacher Yin.
尹老师您好。
Give me the matchbox that was in the hallway yesterday.
把昨天走廊里的火柴盒给我。
you...
你...
...very beautiful. Who are you?
...很漂亮。你是谁？
wheat.
麦。
Where is the beauty?
哪里漂亮了？
He looked like a wet money order.
他看起来就像一张湿汇票。
You're not late, are you? Shut up and go to work.
你没迟到吧？闭嘴去上班吧。
Bottle feet.
瓶脚。
OK
好的。
What?
什么？
- Ouch. - wait for me.
- 哎哟。- 等我。
- goodbye. - goodbye.
- 再见。- 再见。
so you...
那么你...
...Teacher Yin’s husband’s family...
...尹老师的婆家...
so. You are Ms. Yin’s brother.
所以。你是尹女士的弟弟。
You should have told me earlier.
你应该早点告诉我的。
Nice to meet you.
很高兴见到你。
You look as smart as Ms. Yin.
你看起来和尹女士一样聪明。
You look very smart.
你看起来很聪明。
Teacher Yin can't accompany you...
尹老师不能陪你去……
…So he asked me to make sure you go with Soon-ae.
……所以他让我确保你和顺爱一起去。
I also prepared lunch for you and Cikgu Yoon.
我还为你和Cikgu Yoon 准备了午餐。
- Eat later. - I also brought supplies.
- 稍后吃饭。- 我还带来了物资。
That's your lunch.
那是你的午餐。
this is mine.
这是我的。
Chew properly when eating.
吃饭时要适当咀嚼。
If you want to eat my food, come back anytime.
如果你想吃我的食物，随时回来。
Always come, my dear.
永远来吧，亲爱的。
OK Thanks.
好的。谢谢。
That's very good.
那挺好的。
well.
唉。
“Bong Bong Tea Shop”
“Kedai Teh Bong Bong”
- Love letter? - Yes.
- 爱情信？- 是的。
Write a note in it...
写个注释在里面...
...then give it to the guy you're interested in or the girl you like.
...然后送给您感兴趣的人或您喜欢的女孩。
Boys in other classes must do the same.
其他班的男生也必须这样做。
This is very popular in our school.
这在我们学校很流行。
This silly trend further complicates the situation.
这种愚蠢的趋势使情况进一步复杂化。
What?
什么？
"my darling."
“我的宝贝。”
Dear who?
亲爱的谁？
How could you fall in love with him so quickly?
你怎么可以这么快就爱他呢？
I have another matchbox for the new boy.
我还有另一个火柴盒给新来的男孩。
This is for another girl.
这是给另一个女孩的。
If you already love someone else, why give it to him?
如果你已经爱别人了，为什么还要给他呢？
Are you avoiding it?
你在回避吗？
If that's the case, I won't give it to him.
如果是这样，我就不给他了。
Why did the teacher hit me in the mouth?
老师为什么打我的嘴？
come over.
过来。
"Use the toilet like we do."
“像我们一样使用厕所。”
What do I want to do?
我想做什么？
well.
唉。
Why don't you go out?
你为什么不出去呢？
OK I am coming.
好的。我来了。
The main reason why Liu Beomyong was listed as the main suspect is...
柳范龙被列为主要嫌疑人的主要原因是……
...It's because of what he's hiding.
……是因为他隐瞒的事情。
So far nothing. Really?
到目前为止什么都没有。真的吗？
What's this?
这是什么？
sorry...
对不起...
...about yesterday.
……关于昨天。
You were just trying to help me, but I was still cruel.
你只是想帮助我，但我还是很残忍。
It bothered me all night so I couldn't sleep.
它困扰着我一整夜，所以我无法入睡。
therefore.
因此。
You always write...
你总是写信...
...although you will apologize in advance.
……虽然你会提前道歉。
You always do this every time we fight.
每次我们吵架你总是这样做。
I?
我？
yes?
是？
I mean, my mom.
我是说，我的妈妈。
It suddenly occurred to me.
我突然想起来了。
Of course he loved writing.
他当然喜欢写作。
perhaps.
或许。
"Hey Yoon Young. Yi Ni Soon Ae."
“嘿，尹英。伊妮顺爱。”
I don't think that's the reason...
我不认为这就是原因...
...so far.
...到目前为止。
- Hello. - Hello.
- 你好。- 你好。
The second forehead?
第二个额头？
Teacher Yin. that's right.
尹老师。这是正确的。
There is a matchbox in your front pocket. give it to me.
你前面的口袋里有一个火柴盒。把它给我。
What?
什么？
Is there a matchbox in my bag? Where?
我的包里有火柴盒吗？在哪里？
Teachers can't go through other people's schoolbags like this.
老师不能这样翻别人的书包。
“Bong Bong Tea Shop”
“Kedai Teh Bong Bong”
What?
什么？
There is indeed one inside.
里面确实有一个。
You just moved in yesterday...
你昨天刚搬进来...
…So you don’t know the trends.
……所以你不知道趋势。
Why do students take matchboxes from the teahouse?
为什么学生要从茶馆拿火柴盒？
How could it be there?
它怎么可能在那里？
I remembered.
我记得了。
My brother is coming this Sunday...
我弟弟这周日要来...
...and wanted to introduce me to coffee.
...并想向我介绍咖啡。
He took me to a teahouse in town...
他带我去了镇上的一家茶馆......
...I made a tower out of matchboxes there.
...我在那里用火柴盒做了一座塔。
It's so funny, he...
这真是太有趣了，他...
Does your brother still have the Mango key?
你哥哥还保留着芒果钥匙吗？
certainly.
当然。
Mango key?
芒果钥匙？
Why is your bag so light?
为什么你的包这么轻？
Should I bring books on school trips?
学校旅行时我应该带书吗？
Didn't he make lunch?
他没做午饭吗？
not like this.
不是这样的。
Yes, but I forgot to bring it.
是的，但是我忘记带了。
Tell your friends to find my bag.
告诉你的朋友找到我的包。
I go through your bag, so you can go through mine.
我翻你的包，所以你也可以翻我的。
Take the food out of my bag.
把我包里的食物拿走。
Buy soda...
买苏打水...
...can also be purchased for boys in other classes.
...也可以为其他班级的男孩购买。
This is a task for you.
这是给你的任务。
OK
好的。
Rochester's room was engulfed in fire...
罗切斯特的房间被大火吞噬了……
...Jane put it out with a bucket of water.
......简用一桶水将其扑灭。
He held her wrist...
他握住她的手腕……
…and said, “You saved my life.”
……并说：“你救了我的命。”
Where can I stop reading?
哪里可以停止阅读？
Then my mother hit me with a spatula.
然后妈妈就用锅铲打我。
But you just read it.
但你刚刚读过。
He hates me reading.
他讨厌我读书。
He said I was wasting my time doing useless things...
他说我浪费时间做一些无用的事情...
...than doing homework.
...比做作业。
well.
唉。
I want to read all my favorite books...
我想读所有我喜欢的书...
...listen to as much music as you want.
...想听多少音乐就听多少。
I also want to enjoy my coffee. I wish I could live like this.
我也想享受我的咖啡。我希望我能这样生活。
Mom's dream...
妈妈的梦想...
...come true...
...成真...
...through me.
...通过我。
Why?
为什么？
I am very happy.
我很高兴。
When you're done, give me the cup.
完成后，把杯子给我。
Mom is ready to wash up. I'll wash it later.
妈妈准备洗漱了。我稍后再洗。
Just leave it to mom. Leave it to mom.
就交给妈妈吧。交给妈妈吧。
Read as many books as you want.
想读多少书就读多少书。
you leave me
你离开我
you go
你去
Why?
为什么？
what do you mean...
你是什​​么意思...
I just want to know what you heard.
我只是想知道你听到了什么。
give it to me. Let me clean it up.
把它给我。让我把它清理干净。
It doesn't matter.
没关系。
After you get married, you can do it until you get bored.
以后结婚了，可以一直做到厌烦为止。
I will not bother you. Continue reading this book.
我不会打扰你。继续阅读这本书。
I'm tired of hearing this.
我听腻了。
I told my mother many times that I will not get married.
我跟妈妈说过很多次了，我不会结婚。
wheat...
麦...
...give me some time...
...给我时间...
...He can't get it.
……他得不到。
What are you doing?
你在干什么？
I'll give it back to mom now.
我现在就把它还给妈妈。
Mom’s lost time.
妈妈失去的时间。
Everything is let go by you.
一切都被你放下了。
I will give everything back to my mother.
我会把一切还给妈妈。
We'll be late. We must run.
我们会迟到的。我们必须跑。
Why did you go there? Our school is there.
你为什么去那里？我们学校在那里。
Didn't you hear it at the end of get out of class yesterday?
昨天下课的时候你没听到吗？
Today is study tour day.
今天是游学日。
Yes.
是的。
you are right.
你是对的。
wait.
等待。
——Kim Hae-kyung. - Yes.
——金海京。- 是的。
- Lee Eun Ha - Me!
- 李恩河 - 我！
- Park your own car! - yes!
- 自行停车！- 是啊！
- Seo Ji Eun. - Ya.
- Seo Ji Eun. - Ya.
- Yoo Eun-young. - Yes.
- 柳恩英。- 是的。
—— Kwon Soo Kyung. - I.
——权秀京。- 我。
- Bai Yun... - Oh my God.
- 白允... - 天啊。
Teacher Yin.
尹老师。
What?
什么？
what are you doing here?
你在这里做什么？
Shouldn't you check on the arrival of your class?
你不应该检查一下你的班级的到来吗？
Look at it. They are not organized.
看它。他们没有组织。
- look. - you can! hurry up.
- 看。- 你可以！快点。
No. look.
没有。看。
On average, they sit. well.
平均而言，他们坐着。唉。
Boys who don't study always get into trouble.
不学习的男孩总是惹麻烦。
I write clearly to avoid being late. for real?
我写清楚以免迟到。真正的？
He makes me nervous. well.
他让我紧张。唉。
Why did you get down?
你怎么下来了？
Hey!
嘿！
Take it easy.
慢慢来。
Why would the principal match my class with his?
校长为什么要把我的班级和他的班级匹配起来？
well.
唉。
You're right next to the marshmallow. You'd better leave now.
你就在棉花糖旁边。你最好现在就走。
it's useless.
没用的。
Son Jung-sook.
孙正淑.
How do you know the second forehead...
第二额头怎么知道……
...Which one is the Mango Key?
...哪个是芒果钥匙的？
Soon Ai.
很快艾。
The guy from the terminal.
来自航站楼的那个人。
Since we met here again...
自从我们再次在这里相遇...
...means we are dating...
...意味着我们正在约会...
Don't count on it!
不要指望！
Listen, Soon Ae.
听着，顺爱。
Look at his face.
看看他的脸。
You are just wasting your time on this person.
你只是在这个人身上浪费时间。
what are you saying?
你在说什么？
He won't do...
他不会做...
...your life gets better.
...你的生活变得更好。
You look out of breath.
你看上去气喘吁吁。
How about we go now?
我们现在走怎么样？
But then...
但那...
You can't take him anywhere.
你不能带他去任何地方。
Being so out of breath, it's better to take a rest first.
这么气喘吁吁的，还是先休息一下比较好。
Rest first, then climb.
先休息，再爬。
Hey.
嘿。
Soon Ai!
很快艾！
it's useless.
没用的。
The sky looks beautiful.
天空看起来很美丽。
- Ouch. - Ouch.
- 哎哟。- 哎哟。
Why are there so many hills?
为什么有这么多山丘？
Why would anyone come here for a school picnic?
为什么有人会来这里参加学校野餐？
For someone born in 1965, it's an uphill climb.
对于 1965 年出生的人来说，这是一次艰难的攀登。
OK
好的。
You are here today to have fun. So have fun.
你今天来这里是为了玩得开心。所以玩得开心吧。
Don't peek at your textbook...
不要偷偷看你的教科书...
...because you are worried about the college entrance examination.
……因为你担心高考。
-Fan Long. -Fan Long.
-范龙。-范龙。
- Ouch. - This is not good.
- 哎哟。- 这不好。
OK
好的。
Have a great day.
祝你今天过得愉快。
But don't leave the area. OK?
但不要离开这个区域。好的？
- All right. - All right.
- 好吧。- 好吧。
Minister of Entertainment, come out.
娱乐部部长，出来吧。
OK You all know who I am, right?
好的。你们都知道我是谁，对吧？
- yes! - yes!
- 是啊！- 是啊！
What was the highlight of the school picnic?
学校野餐的亮点是什么？
- talent show. - talent show.
- 达人秀。- 达人秀。
that's right. We will have a talent show.
这是正确的。我们将进行才艺表演。
Hey, this is a big moment.
嘿，这是一个重要的时刻。
You have brought me a precious gift.
你给我带来了一份珍贵的礼物。
- OK. Who wants to try it? - I stole it for you...
- 好的。谁想尝试一下？- 我为你偷的...
...from my father.
...来自我父亲。
Hey.
嘿。
But do you think you can do it?
但你认为你能做到吗？
You said you'd never played a real guitar before.
你说你以前从未弹过真正的吉他。
I need to stop playing that invisible guitar.
我需要停止弹奏那把看不见的吉他。
I want to try it.
我想尝试。
No.
不。
Shouldn't we practice it first?
不是应该先练习一下吗？
You might embarrass yourself in front of women.
你可能会在女人面前让自己难堪。
We now start the talent show.
我们现在开始才艺表演。
Everyone applauded.
大家鼓掌。
OK Who wants to try it?
好的。谁想尝试一下？
nobody?
没有人？
well. Is that all you can do?
唉。这就是你能做的一切吗？
I'm tired of practicing.
我厌倦了练习。
OK
好的。
If you rest like everyone else...
如果你像其他人一样休息...
...you'll miss it.
……你会错过的。
- Oh my gosh, eh. garden. - You are all high school students.
- 哦天哪，恩。公园。- 你们都是高中生了。
Don't get too excited.
别太兴奋。
Always thinking about the college entrance examination.
时刻想着高考。
attention!
注意力！
I'm still talking.
我还在说话。
Always thinking about the college entrance examination.
时刻想着高考。
can you stop talking
你能别说话吗
- What? - We didn't hear him sing.
- 什么？- 我们没有听到他唱歌。
Teacher, let’s take a five-minute break!
老师，我们休息五分钟！
- Thanks. - Let's go first.
- 谢谢。- 我们先走。
- where are you going? - Thanks.
- 你要去哪里？- 谢谢。
Hey.
嘿。
This is not good.
这不好。
Did nothing really happen?
真的什么都没发生吗？
No.
不。
I just said two things.
我刚才说了两件事。
Then we met his class teacher.
然后我们就遇到了他的班主任。
Teacher Yin pulled his ears and dragged him away.
尹老师拉着他的耳朵，把他拖走了。
What two sentences did you say to him?
你对他说了哪两句话？
He asked me what kind of man I like.
他问我喜欢什么样的男人。
So I said I like men who can sing.
所以我说我喜欢会唱歌的男人。
Mali.
马里。
Hey.
嘿。
It doesn't matter!
没关系！
- OK. you can! - hurry up!
- 好的。你可以！- 快点！
Does he know how to play guitar?
他知道如何弹吉他吗？
Forget it
别想了
and start talking
并开始说话
stop boring things
停止无聊的事情
- Who is that boy? - Start talking wholeheartedly
- 那个男生是谁？- 开始全心全意地交谈
- He is a new student. - My body is shaking, I'm restless
- 他是个新学生。- 我的身体在颤抖，我焦躁不安
I hesitated, feeling unsure
我犹豫了，感觉不确定
- My face is bright red - My face is bright red
- 我的脸是鲜红的 - 我的脸是鲜红的
- I hesitate, feeling unsure - I hesitate, feeling unsure
- 我犹豫，感觉不确定 - 我犹豫，感觉不确定
I will be alone after breakup
分手后我会一个人
I will cry because my heart is broken
我会因为心碎而哭泣
I know I'll regret it when he leaves
我知道当他离开时我会后悔
- My face is bright red - My face is bright red
- 我的脸是鲜红的 - 我的脸是鲜红的
My body is shaking and I'm restless
我的身体颤抖，我焦躁不安
- I hesitate, feeling unsure - I hesitate, feeling unsure
- 我犹豫，感觉不确定 - 我犹豫，感觉不确定
- My face is bright red - My face is bright red
- 我的脸是鲜红的 - 我的脸是鲜红的
- My body is shaking, I'm restless - My body is shaking, I'm restless
- 我的身体在颤抖，我焦躁不安 - 我的身体在颤抖，我焦躁不安
- I should tell him - I should tell him
- 我应该告诉他 - 我应该告诉他
i should tell him
我应该告诉他
12 plum.
12 梅。
Two days before the first murder.
第一起谋杀案发生前两天。
One of the three suspects has been detained by police.
三名嫌疑人中的一名已被警方拘留。
Two other suspects...
另外两名嫌疑人...
...did not exhibit any unusual movements.
...没有表现出任何异常动作。
The matchbox is the symbol of the criminal.
火柴盒是罪犯的标志。
“Bong Bong Tea Shop”
“Kedai Teh Bong Bong”
It's everywhere.
它无处不在。
well. My head is dizzy.
唉。我的头很晕。
When everything seems confusing...
当一切都显得扑朔迷离时……
...He's arrived.
...他到了。
He is the first victim of the Yu Zhongli serial murder case.
他是宇中里连环杀人案的第一个受害者。
He is there.
他在那。
You remember them, right?
你还记得他们，对吧？
"Personal Information of the Suspect in the 1987 Murder Case"
《1987年杀人案嫌疑人个人资料》
"Lee Joo Young"
“李柱英”
- Principal Yin is here. - Yes.
- 尹校长来了。- 是的。
These boys.
这些男孩。
stand.
站立。
It doesn't matter.
没关系。
Everyone sit down. no problem. sit down.
大家坐下。没问题。坐下。
He will be your trainer for a month.
他将担任您一个月的培训师。
Namdia Lee Joo-young.
那玛迪亚李柱英。
He is a fourth-year student at Seoul National University...
他是首尔国立大学四年级的学生...
...Majoring in Korean Literature.
...主修韩国文学。
He should start tomorrow.
他应该明天开始。
But today I brought him here...
但今天我带他来了...
...so that one day I can introduce him to you.
...以便有一天我可以把他介绍给你。
Give him a round of applause.
给他热烈的掌声。
Where do I see him?
我在哪里看到他？
Teacher Li! You should sing for us too!
李老师！你也应该为我们唱歌！
- Sing for us! - Sing for us!
- 为我们唱歌！- 为我们唱歌！
- Sing for us! - shut up.
- 为我们唱歌！- 住口。
- shut up! - I can sing.
- 住口！- 我会唱歌。
OK please.
好的。请。
you are awesome!
你很棒！
You are wonderful.
你太棒了。
strong wind blowing
刮着大风
A mother sheds tears
一位母亲的泪水流了下来
in this independent world
在这个独立的世界里
A place where one cries for painful revenge
一个人因痛苦的复仇而哭泣的地方
- Human Soul - What is it?
- 人类灵魂 - 它是什么？
- have no idea. Never heard of it. - Become the master of this world
- 不知道。从来没有听说过。- 成为这个世界的主人
- He ruined the mood. -For the freedom of the world
- 他破坏了气氛。- 为了世界的自由
- Even if your heart turns blue - He's charming.
- 即使你的心变蓝 - 他很有魅力。
Don't you think so?
你不这么认为吗？
- Keep Rowing - Why is this song so sad?
- 继续划船 - 为什么这首歌这么悲伤？
Lagu "Dear Qingsong".
Lagu“亲爱的青松”。
Oh, Qingsong
哦，青松
Do you know this song?
你知道这首歌吗？
- No. - Don't sway in the wind
- 没有。- 不要在风中摇晃
- From the East - Why is it so common?
- 来自东方 - 为什么如此常见？
Under the bar where I'm tied up
在我被绑着的酒吧下面
Live until we meet again
活着直到我们再次相遇
- Ouch. - what is that?
- 哎哟。- 那是什么？
well.
唉。
I asked you not to send me off, but you two came?
我叫你们不要送我，你们两个却来了？
If anyone needs to post it, let me post it.
如果有人需要发的话，就让我发吧。
In this case, I will go back.
既然如此，我就回去吧。
No, not you. You should sit here.
不，不是你。你应该坐在这里。
Teacher Park. Don’t you think Miss Yin looks like the same person?
朴老师. 你不觉得尹小姐很像一个人吗？
...Every time I see him?
……每次见到他？
I have no idea.
我不知道。
I rarely watch TV.
我很少看电视。
No, not the people on TV.
不，不是电视里的人。
Look at the people around you.
看看你身边的人。
I have no idea.
我不知道。
I am not interested in the people around me.
我对周围的人不感兴趣。
Why?
为什么？
Teacher Park, I like everything about you...
朴老师，我喜欢你的一切……
…But you’re really wet!
……不过你真的很湿润！
well.
唉。
I...
我...
…Need to come back and mentor students.
……需要回来指导学生。
Let me ask myself first.
我先问问自己。
it's useless.
没用的。
Ugh, I should fire him.
唉，我应该解雇他。
I heard you went to the police station yesterday.
我听说你昨天去了警察局。
- Yes. - Is there anything I can do to help?
- 是的。- 有什么我可以帮忙的吗？
No, everything is fine.
不，一切都很好。
- Thank you for your condolences. - It doesn't matter.
- 谢谢你的慰问。- 没关系。
- Actually it is?
- 其实，是？
I've asked you before.
我以前问过你。
Can I manage new trainee teachers?
我可以管理新的见习老师吗？
OK We decided to do this.
好的。我们决定这样做。
of.
的。
In fact, instead of doing this...
事实上，与其这样做...
No, we are different.
不，我们不一样。
Mali.
马里。
He looks just like my younger self.
他看起来就像我年轻时的自己。
Yes, we do look alike.
是的，我们确实很像。
kindness. Cui, let's go.
恩。崔，我们走吧。
well.
唉。
impossible!
不可能的！
Why does his face look normal?
为什么他的脸看起来很正常？
But I can't find the people I usually see here.
但在这里却找不到平时见到的人。
Alas, son of five moments...
唉，五瞬间之子……
Did Teacher Yin do it himself?
是尹老师自己做的吗？
of.
的。
delicious.
可口的。
correct? my grandmother...
正确的？我的祖母...
Your mom’s kimbap is also delicious.
你妈妈做的紫菜包饭也很好吃。
You talked to me casually after the incident in the lab.
实验室事件发生后，你随意地跟我说话。
Because we are friends.
因为我们是朋友。
that's right.
那是对的。
You can call me any name.
你可以称呼我任何名字。
Bai Runying.
白润英.
"My love and passion for you."
“我对你的爱和热情。”
This is a love letter from the man who was there.
这是一封来自那里的男人的情书。
No.
不。
This is for Soon Ae.
这是给顺爱的。
Accept those gentlemen's feelings.
接受那些先生们的感受。
Thanks.
谢谢。
“Bong Bong Tea Shop”
“Kedai Teh Bong Bong”
This sweet box...
这个甜蜜的盒子...
"You have the most beautiful smile. Call me."
“你的笑容最美，给我打电话。”
“Bong Bong Tea Shop”
“Kedai Teh Bong Bong”
"Women who read are in danger."
“读书的女人很危险。”
I can't say this is a normal thing.
我不能说这是正常的事情。
But that doesn't make sense...
但这没有意义...
…I collected things from 30 years ago by the river.
……我在河边收集了30年前的东西。
Did you pick it up by chance?
你是偶然捡到的吗？
when and where?
何时何地？
"By the river."
“在河边。”
What are you doing so late?
这么晚了你在做什么？
Of course he knew something.
他当然知道一些事情。
“Bong Bong Tea Shop”
“Kedai Teh Bong Bong”
Take it quickly.
快点拿走吧。
- Take it. - I said I didn't want to.
- 拿去。- 我说了我不想。
He doesn't want it! go!
他不想要！去！
useless. OK
无用。好的。
what happen?
发生什么事？
- We'll be back first, teacher. - We'll be back first, teacher.
- 我们会先回来的，老师。- 我们会先回来的，老师。
- We'll be back first. - go home directly.
- 我们会先回来的。- 直接回家。
Have you decided where to live this month?
你决定这个月住在哪里了吗？
Yes, my brother lives around here.
是的，我哥哥就住在这附近。
He is lying.
他在撒谎。
He has no family or relatives.
他没有家人或亲戚。
Why would he cheat?
他为什么要作弊？
so.
所以。
But who knows...
但谁知道...
This is my home phone number.
这是我家里的电话号码。
No.
不。
I tell students to remember my phone number.
我告诉学生们记住我的电话号码。
It's like an emergency number.
这就像一个紧急号码。
If anything happens please feel free to call me.
如果有什么事请随时给我打电话。
Even if it's a trivial thing, I don't care.
即使是微不足道的事，我也不在乎。
Thanks.
谢谢。
But I'm fine because my relatives are here.
但我很好，因为我的亲戚都在这里。
But you shouldn't throw it away.
但你不应该把它扔掉。
OK
好的。
The road conditions are not bad. See you tomorrow.
路况还好。明天见。
Wait, my thermos.
等等，我的保温瓶。
Of course, I was left there.
当然，我被留在了那里。
- Let me go with you. - No.
- 让我和你一起去吧。- 没有。
It's right there, so let me hurry up and go. Wait here.
就在那里，所以我快点走吧。在这儿等着。
Don't run! Be careful.
别跑！当心。
All right!
好吧！
Is it your responsibility to put my brother in a detention center?
你有责任把我弟弟关进看守所吗？
Your brother made it himself.
你弟弟自己做的。
He was imprisoned for his actions.
他因其行为而被监禁。
OK
好的。
So what have you found to be my weakness?
那么你发现我的弱点是什么？
What prompted me to respond.
是什么促使我做出回应。
Useful stuff.
有用的东西。
You already know this.
你已经知道了。
It's so obvious I don't even need to try to find it.
它是如此明显，我什至不需要尝试去找到它。
Soon Ai.
很快艾。
Lee Soon Ae is your weakness.
李顺爱是你的弱点。
But I still don't understand why you are so soft on him.
但我还是不明白为什么你对他如此软弱。
If you already know this, don't forget it.
如果您已经知道，请不要忘记。
My warning from yesterday still stands.
我昨天的警告仍然有效。
About my brother...
关于我弟弟...
You think I'm happy...
你以为我很幸福...
...what happened to him...
……他身上发生了什么事……
...or something else?
...或者其他什么？
are you happy
你快乐吗
I didn't expect to hear these words.
我没想到会听到这些话。
But do I need to know?
但我需要知道吗？
You should try to investigate.
你应该尝试调查一下。
That way you'll know if I'm going to take advantage of your weaknesses...
这样你就会知道我是否会利用你的弱点......
...or not.
...或不。
If so, see you tomorrow, Yoon Young.
如果是的话，明天见，尹英。
- I'm so sorry...
- 实在抱歉...
You go ahead and say it.
你先说吧。
I want to wash my hands first.
我想先洗手。
Because we have a lot of time.
因为我们有很多时间。
OK Because we have a lot of time.
好的。因为我们有很多时间。
if he...
如果他...
…don’t know what will happen here…
……不知道这里会发生什么……
…I have to tell him now.
……我现在必须告诉他。
Because no one knows what will happen.
因为没有人知道会发生什么。
There's something strange going on.
有一些奇怪的事情。
Something must have happened.
肯定发生了什么事情。
impossible.
不可能的。
Why?
为什么？
I just received a call from Principal Yin.
我刚刚接到尹校长的电话。
He was supposed to see Ms. Li, but he could not contact her.
他原本应该去见李女士，但他却联系不上李女士。
I want to go out for a while.
我想出去一会儿。
- wait. - Oh yes.
- 等待。- 哦是的。
Don't go anywhere, just sit at home. OK?
哪里都不要去，就坐在家里。好的？
I will be back soon.
我会很快回来。
Teacher Li.
李老师。
Teacher Trainer.
教师培训师。
It feels weird.
感觉很奇怪。
I know this situation.
我知道这个情况。
"The Man Who Killed Me" Go Mi-sook
《杀了我的人》高美淑
Will not. impossible.
不会的。不可能的。
"My first impression of him..."
“我对他的第一印象……”
"...weird."
“...很奇怪。”
Why does this appear in Gao Meishu's novel?
为什么高美淑的小说里会出现这个？
No.
不。
He can describe...
他可以描述...
...what he had seen in the past.
……他过去所看到的。
My first impression of it...
我对它的第一印象...
...weird.
...很奇怪。
His thick forehead stood out...
他厚厚的额头突出了……
...on his bright and soft face.
……在他明亮而柔软的脸上。
There is also a unique wooden ring…
还有一个独特的木环......
...on his index finger.
……在他的食指上。
Also, his shoes are very dirty...
还有，他的鞋子很脏……
...does not match her neat clothes.
……与她整洁的衣服不相配。
That's why I feel like I know him.
这就是为什么我觉得我认识他。
sorry.
对不起。
Where is Gao Minxiu now?
高珉秀现在在哪里？
where is he
他在哪里
Takamashu.
高珉秀.
Gao Min Xiu!
高珉秀！
Nami, Kim Won Won, Min Hae Kyung,
娜美、金完善、闵海京、
...and Sorboncha. The singer that students look forward to.
...还有索邦查。学生们期待的歌手。
But his gentle yet powerful voice...
但他那温柔而有力的声音……
…He sings that song.
……他唱那首歌。
all of these...
所有这些...
... makes him look special.
...让他看起来很特别。
therefore...
因此...
"Uzheng Department Store"
「宇正百货店」
what are you doing here?
你在这里做什么？
why did you go out
你为什么出去
That woman...
那个女人...
Will he die?
他会死吗？
What?
什么？
That day...
那天...
...I chose him at first sight.
……我第一眼就选择了他。
My first victim...
我的第一个受害者...
...it's beautiful.
...这很漂亮。
That's not true, right?
这不是真的，对吧？
Am I exaggerating?
我很夸张吧？
Are you here because you know something?
你来这里是因为你知道一些事情？
how do you know?
你怎么知道？
This hasn't happened yet.
这还没有发生。
How do you know the here and now?
你怎么知道此时此地？
I think...
我觉得...
… It’s time for us to be honest.
......我们是时候诚实了。
The truth is we met here...
事实是我们在这里相遇了……
...probably not a coincidence.
……可能不是巧合。
"My Perfect Stranger"
《我的完美陌生人》
This is a novel written by Gao Meishu.
这是高美淑创作的小说。
After seeing the student teacher, I had a strange feeling of déjà vu.
看到实习老师后，我有一种奇怪的似曾相识的感觉。
So you read the manuscript again...
所以你再读一遍手稿...
...and everything is the same as in the novel?
……而且一切都和小说里的内容一样？
Do you want Go Mi-sook to be the culprit?
你想让高美淑成为罪魁祸首吗？
The Gao Meishu I know is fully capable of doing all this.
我认识的高美淑完全有能力做到这一切。
Did you release Go Min-soo?
你释放了高民秀？
I just followed the instructions.
我只是按照说明操作。
I don't think I can stay here for long either.
我也不认为我能在这里呆太久。
Who knows my identity?
谁知道我的身份？
"Someone is watching you."
“有人在看着你。”
“Bong Bong Tea Shop”
“Kedai Teh Bong Bong”
You know no one...
你知道没有人...
…So who witnessed your crime?
......那么谁目击了你的犯罪行为？
"Epilogue"
“结语”
Do you know who that person is?
你知道那个人是谁吗？
I said it, didn't I?
我说过了，不是吗？
If you only see one thing and rush...
如果你只看到一件事就匆匆忙忙......
…You end up falling into a lot of traps.
……最终你会陷入很多陷阱。
"My Perfect Stranger"
《我的完美陌生人》